Guide to the Barnaby Conrad Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Barnaby Conrad papers
1951-1975
YCAL MSS 687
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.75
(7 boxes)
The papers consist of writings, printed material, photographs, and artwork by and relating to the American author and artist Barnaby Conrad. Material relates primarily to Conrad's published works Fun While It Lasted (1969); La Fiesta Brava: The Art of the Bull Ring (1953); Matador (1952); and Barnaby Conrad's Encyclopedia of Bullfighting (1961). Among the papers are unsorted typescript and handwritten drafts of writings.
Conrad, Barnaby, 1922-2013
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Barnaby Conrad (Yale 1944), 1965 and 1971.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Barnaby Conrad (1922-)
Barnaby Conrad, American artist and author.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of writings, printed material, photographs, and artwork by and relating to the American author and artist Barnaby Conrad. Material relates primarily to Conrad's published works Fun While It Lasted (1969); La Fiesta Brava: The Art of the Bull Ring (1953); Matador (1952); and Barnaby Conrad's Encyclopedia of Bullfighting (1961). Among the papers are unsorted typescript and handwritten drafts of writings.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: I. 1965 Acquisition, 1951-1952. II. 1971 Acquisition, circa 1960-1975.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Bullfights; Drawings (visual works); Photographs; Scrapbooks; Authors; Conrad, Barnaby, 1922-2013
- 1965 Acquisition, 1951-1952; 1; 0.44; (2 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 160
  - Matador (1952)
    - Original manuscript notes, first typescript draft, typescript draft submitted to Conrad's publishers, proof fragment, correspondence, and printed material, 1951-1952; 7 (Box 1)
    - Two scrapbooks of printed publicity and reviews, 1952; 2 (Box 2)
- 1971 Acquisition, circa 1960-1975; 2; 3.26; (5 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 524
  - Unsorted and unidentified typescript and handwritten writing drafts, undated; 27 (Box 3)
  - Fun While It Lasted (1969), galley proofs (Box 3)
  - Fun While It Lasted (1969), typescript draft, corrected, circa 1968 (Box 4)
  - Unsorted and unidentified typescript and handwritten writing drafts, undated; 6 (Box 4)
    Includes lectures by Conrad
  - La Fiesta Brava: The Art of the Bull Ring (1953), typescript draft, corrected, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Barnaby Conrad's Encyclopedia of Bullfighting (1961)
    - Typescript draft, corrected, 1961; 3 (Box 5)
    - Photographs and line art for publication, undated; 4 (Box 6)
    - Typescript drafts, corrected, circa 1960; 6 (Box 7)